lendingkart.com 2019-06-02

# Privacy Policy | LENDINGKART Group

This document (“Privacy Policy”) is published by virtue of a legal requirement under the provisions of the Information Technology Act, 2000 that require intermediaries to publish the rules and regulations, privacy policy and terms for access or usage of their website/mobile app and is primarily governed by Rule 3 (1) of the Information Technology (Intermediaries Guidelines) Rules, 2011.

Commitment

LENDINGKART intends to protect the privacy of its users and members on its Website and the privacy of the data provided by them to LENDINGKART from time to time. For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, Website means and includes the website ([www.lendingkart.com](https://www.lendingkart.com/)) and mobile application (LENDINGKART Instant Business Loans) of LENDINGKART.

The privacy of our Website users, whether you are our former or existing registered user or merely a visitor to our Website, is important to us and we are strongly committed to your right to privacy and to keeping your personal and other information secure. We encourage you to read our privacy statement to understand what types of personally identifiable information we collect and how we use this information.

What type of information does lendingkart.com collect from you?

Personal Information

For the purpose of providing you services, we require you to enroll yourself on our Website and get yourself registered.

  1. If you choose to become a registered member of our Website, you are required to share your name, e-mail address, gender, date of birth, postal address, phone number, a unique login name, password, password validation, income tax details, marital status, family details, business information and other details shared via application form or via email or via any other medium **(Personally Identifiable Information).**
  2. LENDINGKART may also collect other information specific to provide you service each time such as name, bank statements, KYC documents, personal details, business details, income tax details, marital status, family details and other information via application form or via email or via any other electronic medium or via printed form **(Service Information).**
  3. Additionally, LENDINGKART collects your other details including but not limited to your feedback, suggestions, views, opinions, etc. shared on our Website **(User Information)** that may be shared/volunteered by you on our discussion forums or other pages of our Website. Such information being in the public domain is available for access to all our Website’s users and visitors. You are advised to exercise discretion before you make such details public, as such information is vulnerable to misuse and can be easily misused. LENDINGKART in this regard fully disclaims any liability (ies) or claim(s), which may arise by use/misuse of User Information shared by you, by any third party or any party not known to LENDINGKART.
  4. Information exchanged by you with LENDINGKART in the form of written communication, responses to emails, feedback required from you, participation in discussions, etc. is handled with confidentiality.

INFORMATION COLLECTED THROUGH MOBILE APPLICATIONS

LENDINGKART services are also provided through the Mobile Application. LENDINGKART may collect and use technical data and related information, including but not limited to, technical information about your device, system and application software, and peripherals, that is gathered periodically to facilitate the provision of software updates, product support and other services to you (if any) related to such Mobile Applications.  
When you use our Mobile Application, the Mobile Application may automatically collect and store some or all of the following information from your mobile device (“Mobile Device Information”), in addition to the Device Information, including without limitation:

  1. Your preferred language and country site
  2. The manufacturer and model of your mobile device (including storage, installed apps, )
  3. Your mobile operating system
  4. The type of mobile internet browsers you are using
  5. Your geolocation
  6. Information about how you interact with the Mobile Application and our web site to which the Mobile Application links
  7. Financial Transactional SMS

Non-Personal Information

LENDINGKART also collects certain other information from you on your visit to our Website such as information about your operating system, browser type, the URL of the previous website you visited, list of third-party applications being used by you, your internet service provider and your IP Address **(Non-personal Information)**. This information cannot be easily used to personally identify you. We use Non-personal Information for the purposes including but not limited to troubleshoot connection problems, administer the Website, analyze trends in the market, gather demographic information, to ascertain how our visitors use our Website, including information relating to the frequency of visits to our Website, average length of visits, pages viewed during a visit, ensuring compliance with the applicable law, co-operating with law enforcement activities, etc. This information is used to improve the Website content and performance. You also agree that LENDINGKART may gather usage statistics and usage data from your use of our Website to evaluate your use of our products/services, to improve our products/services, Website content and to ensure that you are complying with the terms of the applicable agreements between you and LENDINGKART. The statistics and data collected may or may not be aggregated. These statistics contain no information that can distinctly identify you.

We may in future also share this information with third party service providers or third party advertisers to measure the overall effectiveness of our online advertising, content, programming and for other bonafide purpose, as we may desire. By usage of our Website you expressly permit LENDINGKART to access such information for one or more purposes deemed fit by LENDINGKART.

Cookies

Similar to other commercial web sites, our Website utilizes standard technology called “Cookies” and Web server logs to collect information about how our Website is used. Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your device’s hard drive. Cookies are only read by the server that places them, and are unable to inter alia run programs on your device, plant viruses or harvest your personal information. Cookies allow Web servers to recognize your device each time you return to our Website including the date and time of visits, the pages viewed, time spent at our Website, and the websites visited just before and just after our Website, verify your registration or password information (in case of registered users) during a particular session so that you do not have to input your password multiple times as you navigate the site and suggest products or services that may interest you. This information is collected on an aggregate basis. None of this information is associated with you as an individual.

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies. By changing the options on your web browser or using certain software programs, you can control how and whether cookies will be accepted by your browser. LENDINGKART understands and supports your right to block any unwanted Internet activity, especially that of unscrupulous websites. However, blocking LENDINGKART cookies may disable certain features on our Website and may make it impossible for you to use certain services available on our Website.

Session Data

We automatically log generic information about your device’s connection to the Internet, which we call “session data”, that is anonymous and not linked to any personal information. Session data consists of information such as the IP address, operating system, type of browser software being used by you and the activities conducted by you on our Website. An IP address is a number that lets device attached to the Internet, such as our web servers, know where to send data back to the user, such as the pages of the site the user wishes to view. We collect session data because it helps us analyze things such as the items visitors are likely to click on most, the manner in which visitors click preferences on our Website, number of visitors surfing to various pages on the Website, time spent by the visitors on our Website and frequency of their visit. It also helps us diagnose problems with our servers and lets us better administer our systems. Although such information does not identify any visitor personally, it is possible to determine from an IP address a visitor’s Internet Service Provider (ISP), and the approximate geographic location of his or her point of connectivity.

Other

We may from time to time add or enhance products/services available on our Website. To the extent these products/services are provided to and used by you, we will use the information you provide in this regard to facilitate the products/service requested. For example, if you email us with a question, we will use your email address, name, nature of the question, etc. to respond to your question. We may also store and publish such information to assist us in making the Website better and easier to use.

Promotional Initiatives

LENDINGKART may have presence on social networking websites including but not limited to LinkedIn, Facebook, Twitter, YouTube and blogs which are promotional and business initiatives to connect to a larger group of people. The domain links contained therein may either direct you to our Website or request your participation by way of feedback, suggestions. LENDINGKART in this regard fully disclaims any liability (ies) or claim(s), which may arise by use/misuse of your feedback, suggestions, views, etc. on any of the aforementioned networking websites or blogs, by any third party whether or not known to LENDINGKART.

Links to Other Sites

Our Website may contain links to other websites. If you click on a third-party link, you will be directed to that website. Note that these external sites are not operated by us. Therefore, we strongly advise you to review the privacy policy of these websites. We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies, or practices of any third-party sites or services.

Does LENDINGKART protect my Personal Information?

LENDINGKART is committed to protecting the privacy and the confidentiality of your Personal Information. Whenever LENDINGKART obtains Personal Information from you, our Website uses commercially reasonable efforts and general industry standards to protect it from any unauthorized access or disclosure. Access to your Personal Information is limited to LENDINGKART’s personnel and such authorized third parties who may host your data on our behalf or may assist us in providing the products and services requested by you. LENDINGKART uses its best endeavours to maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards that aim to protect your information against loss, misuse, damage, modification, and unauthorized access or disclosure. However, LENDINGKART assumes no liability whatsoever for any disclosure of Personal Information due to unauthorized third party access or other acts of third parties, or any other acts or omissions beyond reasonable control of LENDINGKART.

Does LENDINGKART secure the content its users post from other users?

The content that you store, post, or transmit on or through our Website, may be accessed by other users (registered or unregistered), including people that you do not know. The content/images that you post/share on our Website may be prone to misuse by a party not known to you. LENDINGKART in this regard fully disclaims any liability (ies) or claim(s), which may arise by use/misuse of such content, by any third party or any party not known to LENDINGKART. We suggest that you exercise care and caution in communicating with other users and only disclose your information to other users that you know to be trustworthy. You should not assume that your content will be kept private.

How does LENDINGKART use the information that it collects?

Any information share by you is used by us and/or authorized third parties/service partners to support your interaction with us, to offer you services in the best possible manner and to contact you again about other services and products that we offer. By submitting your Personal Information to LENDINGKART, you expressly acknowledge and consent to LENDINGKART to use such information and to process the same in a manner deemed fit by LENDINGKART. This may involve conducting data analysis, research based on reviews about deals, transfer of your Personal Information to third party experts for the purpose of outsourcing services offered to you by LENDINGKART, etc.

What security precautions are in place to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information?

LENDINGKART makes every reasonable effort to preserve the privacy and confidentiality of your information shared with us. We implement standard measures to protect against unauthorized access to and unlawful interception of Personal Information. However, no Internet website can fully eliminate security risks.

We reserve the right to disclose information shared by you without your consent (express or implied) and without any liabilities to you when required or permitted by law and we have a good-faith belief that (i) such action is necessary to comply with an appropriate law enforcement investigation, current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on us or (ii) to conform to the legal requirements, compliance/reporting to administrative and judicial authorities, as may be required (iii) protect and defend the rights or property of the website owners of LENDINGKART, or the users of LENDINGKART, (iv) person(s) or company (ies) who provide certain support services to us, and (v) person(s) or company (ies) who share certain responsibilities/obligations of LENDINGKART. Further, we reserve the right to disclose information shared by you without your consent with entities engaged in providing the credit scores or credit information related services like CIBIL, etc.

I have more questions about privacy policy

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this Website, or your dealings with this Website, please contact us at grievance@lendingkart.com.

Will LENDINGKART change privacy policy in the future?

This policy provides a general statement of the ways in which LENDINGKART aims to protect your information. You may, however, in connection with specific products or services offered by LENDINGKART, be provided with privacy policies or statements that substitute or supplement this policy. The terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy may be changed from time to time, without your consent (express or implied) to reflect changes in our practices concerning the collection and use of your information. The revised Privacy Policy will be effective immediately upon posting to our Website unless otherwise mentioned. This version of the policy is effective from 23rd July, 2018. The revised Privacy Policy shall bind you and it is your sole responsibility to check the same from time to time. You acknowledge that no knowledge of the revised Privacy Policy shall be a defence in any proceedings with regard to the Privacy Policy.

Your Consent

By accessing our Website and using it on a continued basis, you expressly consent and confirm to LENDINGKART collecting, maintaining, using, processing and disclosing your Personal Information and other information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

I have a complaint/concern

In accordance with the relevant provisions of the Information Technology Act, 2000 and Rules made thereunder, the name and contact details of the Grievance Officer who can be contacted with respect to any complaints or concerns including those pertaining to breach of LENDINGKART’s Terms of Use, Privacy Policy and other polices or questions are published as under:

**Grievance Officer Name:** Kumudini Aggarwal  
**Email address:** grievance@lendingkart.com  
The Grievance Officer can be contacted between 10:30 a.m. to 6:00 p.m. from Monday to Friday except on public holidays.
